Register to the Papers of Vladimir and Wanda Toscanini Horowitz
Yale University Music Library
- ITEMS FROM THE LIBRARY OF VLADIMIR HOROWITZ, 1784-1986; Series VII; 21 boxes (8.75')
  - Manuscript and Printed Music From the Library of Vladimir Horowitz, VII.A
    - Le Chant de la Mer. Paris: Durand & Cie, 1920., Samazeuilh, Gustave (Box 97, Folder 133)
      Plate number: D. & F. 9820
      Inscribed in ink by composer on first page, dated Noël 1933.
    - Equisses.. pour le Piano. Paris: Durand & Cie, 1945., Samazeuilh, Gustave (Box 97, Folder 133)
      Plate number: D. & F. 13,223
      Inscribed in ink by composer on first page, dated Oct. 51.
    - Nocturne. Paris: Durand & Cie, 1938., Samazeuilh, Gustave (Box 97, Folder 133)
      Plate number: D. & F. 12,839
      2 copies. Both copies inscribed in ink by composer on first page, dated Mai 38, Juli 38.
    - Oeuvres de Dominique Scarlatti pour le clavecin ou pianoforte, cahier 8. Vienna: Bureau d'Arts et d'Industrie, n.d., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757
      Plate number: 509
      (Oeuvres de Dom. Scarlatti)
      Répertoire International des Sources Musicales (RISM) S-1216. 8 volumes in all. No copy of any volume in the U.S.A. Only 7 copies of volume 8 worldwide.
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume I. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1975., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 97, Folder 134)
      186 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 541
      (Opere complete per clavicembalo in 10 volumi e un supplemento)
      "CBS record" in pencil on cover.
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume II. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1975., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 97, Folder 135)
      134 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 542
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume III. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1972., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 97, Folder 136)
      192 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 543
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume IV. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1975., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 98, Folder 137)
      187 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 544
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume V. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1974., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 98, Folder 138)
      182 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 545
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume V. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1983., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 98, Folder 139)
      199 p.
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume VI. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1974., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 98, Folder 140)
      195 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 546
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume VII. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1973., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 98, Folder 141)
      213 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 547
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume VIII Milano: G. Ricordi, 1972., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 98, Folder 142)
      Plate number: E. R. 548
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume IX. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1975., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 99, Folder 143)
      218 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 549
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, volume X. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1973., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 99, Folder 144)
      208 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 550
    - Opere complete per clavicembalo, supplemento. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1974, repristino 1981., Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757 (Box 99, Folder 145)
      197 p.
      Plate number: E. R. 551
      (Opere complete per clavicembalo in 10 volumes e un supplemento)
    - [Untitled] (Box 99, Folder 146)
      p. 61-92
      Plate number: 10463
      Pages from ?
      Markings on pp. 88-90 (Impromptu, Op. 142).
    - Fantasie für Klavier zu vier Händen, op. 103. Munchen-Duisburg: G. Henle Verlag, 1958., Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 (Box 99, Folder 146)
      2 copies. One copy inscribed in ink on title page, signed "Byron", dated October 1st, 1985. Other copy inscribed in ink on title page by Tom & Lynne Frost, dated Oct. 1, 1985.
    - Drei Klavierstücke. Impromptus aus dem Nachlass. München: G. Henle Verlag, 1955., Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 (Box 99, Folder 146)
      Inscribed in ink on cover by François-Marie Banier, dated 14 Mar. '84.
    - Arabesque, op. 18; Blumenstuck, op. 19; Romances, op.28. New York: G. Schirmer, 1945., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 147)
      Plate number: 40904
      (Schirmer's library of musical classics, volume 1686)
    - Carnaval, op.9. New York: G. Schirmer, 1893., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 148)
      Plate number: 10747
      (Schirmer's Library of Musical Classics, volume 89: Robert Schumann's complete works for the pianoforte.)
      Critically revised and fingered by Max Vogrich. Fragile.
    - Concert pour piano seul, composé et dédié a M. Ignace Moscheles, oeuvre 14., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 149)
      Photocopy of manuscript compiled and edited by Fredrick Zeigler and Howell Price, copyright 1974. Included is letter to Vladimir Horowitz from editors, after title page.
    - [Études Symphoniques (Sketches)] 20 Var. der Symph. Etuden, ca. 1834., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856
      [6] sheets of music; 27 x 33 cm.
      Holograph in ink with pencil additions.
      Two photographs and a negative of Var. I laid in.
      Cataloged separately, Miscelaneous manuscript 301.
    - Etudes de concert d'après caprices de Paganini, op. 10. Leipzig: Rob. Forberg, 1913., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 150)
      Plate number: 6488
      (Eugen d'Albert's Klavierabenden)
      Markings pp. 25, 27.
    - [Fantasie, piano, op. 17, C major] Fantasie für das Pianoforte, componirt und Herrn Franz Liszt zugeeignet, op. 17. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, [1839]., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856
      Plate number: 6053
    - [Fantasie, piano, op. 17, C major] Phantasie für Klavier zu 2 Händen, op. 17. Neu revidiert von Adolf Ruthardt. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 151)
      Plate number: 8641
    - Kinderscenen (Scenes from childhood), op. 15. New York: G. Schirmer, 1893., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 152)
      Plate number: 10508
      (Schirmer's library of musical classics, volume 101: Robert Schumann complete works for the pianoforte.)
      Edited and fingered by Max Vogrich.
    - Klavierwerke: Band III. München: G. Henle Verlag, 1976., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 152)
      231 p.
    - Kreisleriana, op. 16. New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., 1894., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 152)
      Plate number: 11071
      (Schirmer's library of musical classics, volume 95)
      Not bound, pages were encased in plastic sheets. Critically revised and fingered by Max Vogrich.
    - Sonata II: op. 14. New York: G. Schirmer, 1902., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 153)
      Plate number: 15961
      (Schirmer's Library of Musical Classics, volume 103-105. Robert Schumann's sonatas for the pianoforte, op. 11, op. 14, op. 22.)
    - Toccata für klavier zu 2 Händen, op. 7. Neue Ausgabe von Emil von Sauer. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 153)
      Plate number: 10553
      Markings, p. 12.
    - Wilder Reiter, op. 68, no. 8 New York: G. Schirmer, n.d., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 (Box 99, Folder 153)
      Plate number: 13036d
      (Robert Schumann compositions for the piano, first series.)
    - Schweizer Klaviermusik aus der Zeit der Klassik und Romantik. Leipzig und Zürich: Gebruder Hug & Co., n.d. (Box 100, Folder 154)
      Plate number: G.H. 8238
      Note inscribed on title page in German, dated 31 Dec. 1937.
    - Album of Alexander Scriabin masterpieces. Selected compositions chosen from his best piano works. New York: Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1941., Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915 (Box 100, Folder 155)
      Markings by Vladimir Horowitz.
    - Complete preludes and etudes for pianoforte solo. New York: Dover Publications, Inc., 1973., Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915 (Box 100, Folder 155)
      250 p.
    - 24 preludes, op. 11. New York: Edward B. Marks, 1942., Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915 (Box 100, Folder 156)
      38 p.
      Markings (by Vladimir Horowitz?)
    - 24 Preludes for piano. Moskow: 1954., Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915 (Box 100, Folder 156)
      Plate number: M. 18650 G. M. 19016 G.
    - 6me Sonate pour Piano, op. 62. Berlin: Russischer Musikverlag, n.d., Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915 (Box 100, Folder 156)
      Plate number: R. M. V. 175
    - Sonate no. 3, en fa-dièse mineur pour piano, op. 23. Leipzig: M. P. Belaieff, 1898., Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915 (Box 100, Folder 157)
      Plate number: 1875
      Apparently first edition.
    - Sonate-Fantaisie No. 2, en Sol-dièse mineur pour piano, op. 19. Leipzig: M. P. Belaieff, 1898., Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915 (Box 100, Folder 158)
      Plate number: 1605
      Very fragile.
    - Concerto: pour piano avec orchestre: Op. 35 / D. Schostakowitsch. Moscou: Édition de musique de l'état R.S.F.S.R., 1934., Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975
      59 p.
      Plate number: M. 14332g.
      1st ed.
    - Trois Danses Fantastiques, op. 1. Moscou: Staatsmusikverlag, 1937., Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975 (Box 100, Folder 159)
      Plate number: M. 7078 G.
      "Vladimir Horowitz" on front cover.
    - Ledi Makbet: opera: op. 29. Moskva: Gosudarstvennyi Muzykal'nyi Teatr, n.d., Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975 (Box 100, Folder 160-163)
      3 volumes (act I, 74 p.; act II, 97 p.; act III 82 p.; act IV, 66 p.)
      Very fragile. "Lady MacBeth of Minsk" in pen on cover of all volumes.
      Negative microfilm laid in
    - 24 Preliudii: Op. 34: dlia fortepiano / D. Shostakovich. Moskva: Gosudarstvennoe Muzykal'noe Izdatel'stvo, 1934., Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975
      Plate number: M. 14215g.
    - 24 Preliudii i fugi: dlia fortepiano: Soch. 87 / D. Shostakovich. Moskva: Gosudarstvennoe Muzykal'noe Isdatel'stvo, 1952., Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975
      Two volumes.
      Pl. nos.: M. 23149g, M. 23150g.
    - Sonate: pour piano: Op. 12 / D. Schostakowitsch. Moscou: Édition de musique de l'état R.S.F.S.R., 1935., Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975
      Plate number: M. 7374g.
    - Finlandia, op. 26, nr. 7. New York: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1917., Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957 (Box 101, Folder 164)
      Plate number: E.B. 2415
      Inscribed in ink inside front cover, no signature.
    - Dance card for piano. Bryn Mawr: Merion Music, Inc. Theodore Presser Co., 1986., Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 (Box 101, Folder 165)
      Plate number: 440-40012
      Inscribed in ink by composer on title page, dated 10.28.86.
    - Star spangled banner. New York: Robbins Music Corporation, 1941., Smith, John Stafford, 1750-1836 (Box 101, Folder 166)
      Plate number: SH 2207-3
      Inscribed in ink on cover, sigend Harry Rosenthal.
    - Stars and stripes forever., Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932 (Box 101, Folder 166)
      Photocopy of manuscript. Transcription of Sousa-Horowitz
      Stars and stripes forever by Ian Hobson.
    - Stars and stripes forever. Philadelphia: John Church Company, 1897., Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932 (Box 101, Folder 166)
      Plate number: 30111-4
      Piano transcription.
    - Stars and stripes forever., Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932 (Box 101, Folder 166)
      Manuscript. [pages from Vladimir Horowitz's transcription?]
    - Stars and stripes forever. Philadelphia: John Church Company, 1897., Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932 (Box 101, Folder 166)
      Plate number: 34002
      Reduced band conductor's score.
    - Sonata. Wien: Universal-Edition A. G., 1930., Steinert, Alexander (Box 101, Folder 167)
      Plate number: U.E.9998
      Inscribed in ink by composer on title page, dated 1930.
      Dedicated to Vladimir Horowitz.
    - Trio pour violon, violoncelle et piano. Wien: Universal-Edition A. G., 1931., Steinert, Alexander (Box 101, Folder 167)
      Score (40 p.) + 2 parts.
      Plate number: U.E. 5307
      Piano part inscribed in ink by composer on first page, dated 1932.
    - Burleske D-moll für Pianoforte und Orchester. Leipzig: Steingraber Verlag, 1894., Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949
      Plate number: 515a
      Arranged for two pianos.
      First edition of 2-piano arrangement.
    - Quatre Etudes: pour Piano: Op. 7: No. 2 / par I. Strawinsky. Leipzig: P. Jurgenson; Rob. Forberg, [1910]., Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971
      Plate number: 33867.
    - Quatre Etudes pour Piano, op. 7. No. 3. Leipzig: P. Jurgenson, [1910]., Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971
      Plate number: 33868
    - Trois mouvements de Petrouchka. Transcription pour piano-solo par l'auteur. Moscou: Édition Russe de Musique, [1922]., Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 (Box 101, Folder 168)
      Plate number: R.M.V. 400
      First edition of solo piano arrangement.
    - L'oiseau de feu ballet. Danse infernale, Berceuse, Final. Mainz: B. Schott's Sohne, 1934., Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 (Box 101, Folder 168)
      Plate number: B-S-S 34118
      Transcriptions pour Piano par Guido Agosti. Inscribed in ink by Guido Agosti on title page, dated December 1934.
    - Evgenii Onegin / Pl Chaikovskii; Redaktsiia Ivana Shisnova. Moskva: Gosudarstvennoe Muzykal'noe Izdatel'stvo, 1946., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 (Box 101)
      1 vocal score (295 p.).
      Inscribed to Vladimir Horowitz from Sonia, 1953 Jan. 12.
    - Fantaisie de Concert pour Piano avec accompagnement d'Orchestre ou d'un second Piano, op. 56. Leipzig: D. Rahter, 1923., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 (Box 101, Folder 169)
      Plate number: 2977
      Includes Beilage for pages 28-31.
    - Fantaisie de Concert pour Piano avec accompagnement d'Orchestre ou d'un second Piano, op. 56. Leipzig: D. Rahter, n.d., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 (Box 101, Folder 170)
    - Izbrannye Sochineniia. dlia fortepiano. Vypusk II/ P. I. Chaikovskii; Redaktsiia Ia. Mil'shteina i K. Sorokina. Moskva: Gosudarstvennoe Muzykal'noe Izdatel'stvo, 1949., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 (Box 101, Folder 171)
      Plate number: M. 19934 G.
    - Romance, op. 5. Berlin: Adolphe Fürstner, n.d., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 (Box 101, Folder 171)
      Plate number: F. 2258
    - Shestaia simfoniia pateticheskaia. Moskva: PML Instituta "Giprotis", 1962., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893
      Facsimile. Photograph of P. I. Tchaikovsky glued to front cover verso. Photocopy of letter from A. N. Skriabin's wife, Vera Ivanovna, 25 May 1902, laid in.
    - Dvie piesni: op. 2 / Musyka Gr. Sergieia Tolstogo. Moskva: Gravirovano i Pechatano V Notopechatnie P. Iurgensona, 1911., Tolstoi, Sergei
      Pl. nos.: 1543, 1544.
      Inscribed to Wanda Landowska by Serge Tolstoi.
    - Prelude and love death from "Tristan und Isolde". Miami: Edwin F. Kalmus, n.d., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883 (Box 101, Folder 172)
      Conductor's score. Inscribed in ink on inside front cover, signed Tom & Lynne [Frost], dated Oct. 1, 1989.
    - Aufforderung zum Tanz für pianoforte, op. 65. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826 (Box 101, Folder 173)
      Plate number: V. A. 2178.
      Mit Arabesken für den Konzertvortrag von Carl Tausig. Neu herausgegeben mit erganzenden Bezeichnungen von Xaver Scharwenka.
    - Concertstück for pianoforte with orchestra accompaniment arranged for a second piano, op. 79. New York: G. Schirmer, 1915., Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826 (Box 101, Folder 173)
      Plate number: 25557
      (Schirmer's library of musical classics, v.1189)
      Vladimir Horowitz's autograph on front cover?
    - Polacca for the piano forte. London: s. Chappell, n.d., Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826
      Plate number: 2272
    - Four loose-leaf notebooks containing photocopies of published music, repertoire for: "Music for film product. 1985" (Box 102, Folder 174)
      Contents: Bach-Busoni, G Minor Chorale Prelude. -- Rachmaninoff, Op. 23, No. 5. V. -- Chopin, Valse, Op. 69, Nr. 1. -- Schubert, Impromptu. -- Liszt, Au Bord D'une Source. -- Rachmaninoff, Prelude, Op. 32, No. 12. -- Schumann, Noveletten, Opus 21.
    - "Sunday, April 20, 1986, Moscow - Bolshoizall - 4:00 P.M." (Box 102, Folder 175)
      Contents: Scarlatti, Sonata in B Minor, Longo 33, Sonata in E Major, Longo 23, and Sonata in E Major, Longo 224. -- Rachmaninoff, Prelude in G Major, Op. 32, and Prelude in G sharp Minor, Op. 32. -- Scriabin, Etude in C sharp Minor, Op. 2, and Etude in D sharp Minor, Op. 8. -- Schubert, Impromptu in B flat, Op. 142, No. 3. -- Schubert-Liszt, Valse Caprice, No. 6, Soirées de Vienne (d'Après Franz Schubert). -- Liszt, Sonnetto del Petrarcca in E Major, No. 104. -- Rachmaninoff, Polka.
    - "1987 Amsterdam Vienna Berlin Hamburg" (Box 102, Folder 176)
      Contents: Schubert-Liszt, Valse. -- Schumann, Kinderszenen. -- Chopin, Polonaise, Op. 53, and Scherzo, Op. 20. -- Scriabin, Etude, Op. 2, No. 12. -- Liszt, Consolation.
    - "First Recital May 2nd" (Box 102, Folder 177)
      Chopin, Quatrième Ballade, Op. 52. -- Liszt, Ballade II. -- Chopin, Valse brillante, Op. 34, No. 2, Valse, Op. 64, No. 2, Polonaise-Fantasie, op. 63, Première Ballade, Op. 23. -- Schumann, Romance, Op. 28, No. 2. -- Rachmaninoff, Sonata, Op. 36.
    - List in Vladimir Horowitz's hand labeled "Scarlatti Sonatas on CBS Records" (Box 102, Folder 178)
    - Catalog of music originally in Vladimir Horowitz's personal collection (Box 103–105)
      2 index card trays.
      Notes with additional information have been added to some cards, including a note for items not found. For items found but with no card, a card has been added.
  - Music from the Library of Vladimir Horowitz, VII.B
    Given to the Yale University Music Library on December 17, 1991
    - [Lieder ohne Worte, op. 19, no. 2], Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847
      [4] p. of music; 14 x 18 cm.
      Holograph in ink.
      At end: Rom d. 11 Dec. 1830.
      With: Letter from Mendelssohn-Bartholdy to Lannoy, 1846 Feb. 14, see C. Correspondence
      Cataloged separately
    - [Happy birthday to you; arr.] [Happy birthday to you] / [arranged by Arturo Toscanini], ca. 1947 October 1., Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957
      Holograph in ink [red and blue]
      Inscription: "A Volodia October 1 1947"
      On stationery with Arturo Toscanini's letterhead
      See: I. CORRESPONDENCE. Toscanini, Arturo
    - [Untitled], Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957
      [2] p.; 37 cm.
      Holograph, signed, in ink
      Inscription on title page: "To Sonia Horowitz from Beethoven's substitute"
      Words on title page: "Sonia don't forget your nonno, send him quick your composition, otherwise he will be angry and you will lose Riverdale -- Buenos Aires. 29 Giugno 1941"
  - Correspondence from the Library of Vladimir Horowitz, VII.C
    Given to the Yale University Music Library on December 17, 1991, and subsequently transferred to Misc. Ms. 372, Miscellaneous Letters and Documents File.
    - [Letter] 1866 Sep. 4, [S.l.], [to] Cosima [Liszt], [S.l.] [manuscript] / [Franz Liszt]., Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886
      [4] p. on 1 leaf; 19 x 25 cm.
      Holograph signed.
      In French.
      Sheet with laid in with note "written by Daniele Liszt Thode her gift to Vladimir Horowitz."
    - [Letter] 1869 Feb. 20, Weimar, [to] Dr. [Carl] Gille, Jena [manuscript] / Franz Liszt., Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886
      [2] p. on 1 leaf; 18 cm.
      Envelope with stamp and postmark laid in.
    - [Letter] 1878 June 1, Weimar, [to] [?], [S.l.] [manuscript] / Franz Liszt., Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886
      [1] leaf; 18 cm.
      In German.
    - [Letter] 1885 Apr. 9, Budapest, [to] ?, [S.l.] [manuscript] / Franz Liszt., Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886
      [2] p. on 1 leaf; 20 cm.
    - [Letter] [1880s?], Weimar, [to] Baronesse Stephanie von Peret?, Narbonne [manuscript] / Franz Liszt., Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886
      [1] leaf; 13 cm.
      Address appears on fourth page of the folded sheet.
    - [Calling card with note], [S.l.], [to] Franz Korbay?, [S.l.] [manuscript] / Franz Liszt., Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886
      [1] leaf; 8 x 12 cm.
    - [Letter] 1846 Feb. 14, Leipzig,[to] Baron [Edoardo] Lannoy, Wien [manuscript] / Felix Mendelssohn-Bartholdy., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847
      [1] leaf; 28 cm.
      Address, postmark, and seal, on fourth page of folded leaf.
      With: Albumleaves with holograph manuscript of [Lieder ohne Worte, op. 19, no. 2], for full cataloging see A. Music.
    - [Letter] 1884 Mar. 2, London, [to ?], [S.l.] [manuscript] / Clara Schumann., Schumann, Clara
      [8] p. on [2] leaves; 23 cm.
      English synopsis of letter laid in.
    - [Letter] 1844 Nov. 28, Dresden, [to] Antonio Bazzini, Leipzig [manuscript] / Robert Schumann., Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856
      [1] p. on 1 leaf; 24 cm.
      Address, seal, and postmarks on fourth page of folded leaf.
      Italian translation (typescript) laid in.
      Note laid in [in fragile condition].
    - [Letter] 1875 Sep. 21-Nov. 3, Moscou, [to] [Hans von Bülow], [S.l.] [manuscript] / Peter Ilich Tchaikovsky., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893
      [3] p. on 1 leaf; 22 cm.
    - [Letter] 1893 Sep. 15-27, Spassvoïe?, [to] Sigismund de Stojowsky, Paris [manuscript] / Peter Ilich Tchaikovsky., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893
      [4] p. on 1 leaf; 14 x 16 cm.
      Envelope with stamps and postmarks laid in.
    - [Letter] 1893 Oct. 7, Moscou,[to] Sigismund [Stojowski], [S.l.] [manuscript] / Peter Ilich Tchaikovsky., Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893
      [4] p. on 1 leaf; 18 cm.
- AWARDS, 1928-1991; Series VIII; 27 boxes (11.25')
  The awards are listed alphabetically by issuing organization, then chronologically. They include certificates, plaques, medals, statuettes, paperweights, ice buckets, trophies, a book, a vase, and a SONY Walkman. The oversize awards are housed in oversize boxes at the end (142-151, 160) with the exception of 2 awards which are too large for the oversize boxes. These 2 awards are housed separately in the Yale University Music Library (designated ov in the register). Correspondence accompanying the awards has been copied and the originals (with cross-references) filed with I.A. CORRESPONDENCE - Personal. The copies remain with the awards.
  - Accademia Nazionale di Santa Cecilia
    - Accademico Onorario di Santa Cecilia, Rome, 1965 June 13 (Box 142)
      Framed certificate
  - Academy of Television Arts and Sciences Television Academy Awards - Primetime Emmy Awards
    - Nomination for Outstanding Variety or Musical Program, 1968-1969 (Box 106, Folder 1)
      "Vladimir Horowitz: A Television Concert at Carnegie Hall" 9/22/68
      CBS - mounted certificate
    - Outstanding Achievement in Coverage of Special Events, 1978-1979 (Box 145)
      "Horowitz Live!" NBC - trophy
    - Nomination for Outstanding Classical Program 1981-1982 (Box 106, Folder 2)
      "Horowitz in London: A Royal Concert" 5/22/82 Public Broadcasting Service (PBS) - certificate
    - Outstanding Classical Program in the Performing Arts, 1986-1987 (Box 145)
      "Vladimir Horowitz: The Last Romantic" 5/15/87 Public Broadcasting Service (PBS) - trophy
  - Billboard
    - #1 in the Nation Award, ca. 1967 (Box 142)
      Mounted certificate
    - Paperweight with engraving in gold: TOP CLASSICAL ALBUMS - #1 Horowitz in Moscow... - #2 The Studio Recordings... - #3 The Last Romantic, 1986 Nov. 22 (Box 106)
  - Bohemians
    - Silver vase with inscription: To Vladimir Horowitz with grateful appreciation from "The Bohemians" (New York Musicians Club)..., 1928 Apr. 2 (Box 145)
  - CBS/SONY Records Inc.
    - Plexiglass paperweight, 1970 Best Classical Performance /Instrumental Soloist - Kreisleriana (Box 106)
    - Framed disc, 1970 Best Classical Performance /Instrumental Soloist - Kreisleriana (Box 187)